

SUMMARY

Highly accomplished IT professional with over 20 years of experience in the Information Technology field. Holding a Master's degree in Engineering.

Fully proficient in both backend and frontend SAP development along with knowledge of the methodology. Implementing an analytical and disciplined approach to development projects, coupled with the ability to work independently without supervision.

Software development has been a significant aspect of my career and is an area where I have continually developed and improved over the years.

CONTACTS

E-MAIL:

mikalai.kazlou.mail@gmail.com

TEAMS:

mikalai.kazlou@outlook.com

LINKEDIN:

Mikalai Kazlou

EDUCATIONAL COURSES

The Rolling Scopes School JavaScript / Frontend 2023

EPAM Training Center Modern SAP Development2021

ACHEVEMENTS

Top SAPper of the Year EPAM Systems2024

EPAM Belarus One-of-a-Kind EPAM Systems 2022

MIKALAI KAZLOU

SAP Lead Software Engineer (Development Team Lead; Software Engineering Manager)

EDUCATION

Belarusian National Technical University (Master's degree) Information Technologies and Robotics Faculty Automated information processing systems 2005 — 2006

Belarusian National Technical University (Bachelor's degree) Information Technologies and Robotics Faculty Automation of financial operations 2000 — 2005

WORK EXPERIENCE

EPAM Systems Lead Software Engineer 2021 — present

Unitary Enterprise A1
Senior Software Engineer
2010 — 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Strong Core ABAP programming skills including ABAP OO and Design Patterns
- Good experience in CDS, AMDP, BOPF, BAPI/RFC, Web-services (SOAP, REST, OData)
- Solid knowledge of Frontend development and JavaScript stack (JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, SAPUI5)
- Dotted experience in Cloud Application Programming Model (CAP), RESTful Application Programming Model (RAP)
- Good understanding of ABAP Test Cockpit, ABAP Performance Tuning, Runtime Analysis Tools and Techniques
- Knowledge of SAP system functionality (MM, SD, FI, RE-FX modules)

SOFT SKILLS

- Ability to play role of Development Team Leader, Resource Manager
- · Conducting technical interviews with external candidates
- Agile development experience with expert understanding of application and software architecture
- Ability to work both independently and as a part of international project team
- Disciplined and analytical approach to development projects and ability to work without supervision
- Mentoring and conducting knowledge transfer sessions for less experienced colleagues
- Quickly learning and remembering new information

LANGUAGES

Russian: Native

English: **B2** (Upper Intermediate)

Frontend Portfolio

https://mikalai-kazlou.github.io/portfolio/

Skills

Skills	Expert	Advanced	Intermediate
Academic Disciplines / Applied Sciences			
Clean Code		✓	
Design patterns		✓	
Object-oriented Programming	✓		
Performance Psychology		✓	
Software Development	✓		
Software Maintenance		✓	
Software Quality		✓	
SOLID (object-oriented design principles)		✓	
Academic Disciplines / Humanities			
English		✓	
Russian	✓		
Business Functions / Corporate Communications			
Interviewing		✓	
Engineering Practices / Advanced Technology			
Cloud Fundamentals			√
Debugging	✓		
Engineering Excellence			✓
GenAl Pair Programming			✓
Generative AI Fundamentals			✓
Prompt Engineering			✓
Prompt Engineering for Dev Productivity			✓
Software Design		_	
Software Development Methodology in Engineering		_	
Software Engineering Knowledge & Experience		_	
Software Engineering Practices		✓	
Software Engineering Processes		✓	
Troubleshooting	✓		
Engineering Practices / Data & Analytics			
Data Solution Architecture			✓
Database Performance			✓
Engineering Practices / Digital Engagement			
Content Creation			✓
Front-End Development			✓
Engineering Practices / Management			
Engineering Management			✓
Engineering Practices / Quality Engineering			
Performance Analysis		✓	
Unit Testing			✓
Leadership & Soft Skills / Communication			
Communication			√
Content Delivery			
Giving and Receiving Feedback		✓	
Negotiations			
Presenting			
Leadership & Soft Skills / Consultancy			
Client Relationship Management			/

Skills	Expert	Advanced	Intermediate
Consultancy			✓
Leadership & Soft Skills / Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion			
Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion			✓
Leadership & Soft Skills / Growth Mindset			
Adaptability			✓
Continuous learning			✓
Leadership & Soft Skills / Leadership			
Developing Others			✓
Driving Change and Innovation			✓
Leadership			✓
Mentoring			✓
Professional Development Planning			✓
Leadership & Soft Skills / Ownership			
Ownership			✓
Result-orientation		✓	
Self-Management		✓	
Time Management		✓	
Leadership & Soft Skills / Teamwork and Collaboration			
Team Management			✓
Teamwork and Collaboration			✓
Managerial / General Management			
Agile		✓	
Kanban		✓	
Scrum		✓	
Managerial / People Management			
Bench Management			✓
Career Advising			✓
Compensation Management			✓
Conducting one-on-one meetings			✓
Employee Recognition			✓
Employee Retention			✓
Exit Management			✓
Interviewing and Hiring			✓
Motivation			✓
Onboarding and Adaptation			✓
People Management			✓
Performance Development			✓
Unit Management			✓
Technologies / Computer Languages			
ABAP	✓		
CSS			✓
HTML			✓
JavaScript			✓
SASS/SCSS			✓
SQL	✓		
TypeScript			✓
XML		✓	
Technologies / Frameworks			
ABAP Web Services			√
QUnit			_
OPA5			✓
SAPUI5			✓
Unit Testing Tools			✓

Skills	Expert	Advanced	Intermediate
Webpack			√
Technologies / Operating System			
Linux			✓
Microsoft Windows		✓	
Technologies / Platforms			
NPM			✓
Eclipse with ABAP Development Tools		✓	
SAP ABAP Platform	✓		
SAP NetWeaver	✓		
SAP Business Technology Platform			✓
Technologies / SAP			
ABAP Core	\checkmark		
ABAP Dictionary	✓		
ABAP Objects	✓		
ABAP RESTful Programming Model (RAP)			✓
ABAP Syntax 7.5+		✓	
ABAP Unit Tests			✓
ABAP Workbench Tools	✓		
ALV Control	✓		
AMDP			✓
Background Processing System		✓	
Business Object Processing Framework (BOPF)		✓	
Changing the SAP Standard		✓	
Desktop Office Integration			✓
Enhancement Framework		✓	
HANA			✓
Internet Application Server			✓
LSMW			✓
OpenSQL	✓		
SAP ABAP in S/4HANA		✓	
SAP API and Integration			✓
SAP BAPI/RFC		✓	
SAP Basis			✓
SAP Business Application Studio			✓
SAP Business Workflow			✓
SAP CAP Annotations			✓
SAP CAP Authorization and Access Control			✓
SAP CAP based Node.JS			✓
SAP CAP CDS			✓
SAP CAP Deploy			✓
SAP CO Technical			✓
SAP Core Data Services		✓	
SAP ERP	✓		
SAP FI Technical		✓	
SAP Fiori			✓
SAP Fiori Elements			✓
SAP Fiori Elements: Flexible Programming Model			✓
SAP Fiori launchpad			✓
SAP Frontend			✓
SAP Gateway		✓	
SAP GUI	✓		
SAP HANA SQL and SQL Script			✓
SAP Interactive Forms			

Appendix 1

Skills	Expert	Advanced	Intermediate
SAP MM Technical		✓	
SAP NetWeaver	✓		
SAP Query			✓
SAP SD Technical		✓	
SAP UI Development Tools			✓
SAP Web Services		✓	
SAP XML library			✓
Smartforms		✓	
Technologies / Solutions			
1C Enterprise		✓	
Chrome DevTools			✓
ESLint			✓
GitHub			✓
Jira			✓
Microsoft Excel		✓	
Microsoft Word		✓	
Postman		✓	
SoapUI (Open Source)			✓
Visual Studio Code			✓
Technologies / Standards			
Git			✓
JSON			✓
OData		✓	
REST API		✓	
SOAP		✓	
UML			✓
Technologies / Tools			
Code Quality Tools			✓
Web UI Testing Tools			✓
Technologies / Web/Application Server			
Node.js			✓

Work Experience

May-2024 - Till now - EPAM Systems, https://www.epam.com

Customer: Novocure (Life Sciences & Healthcare)

Project Roles: Development Team Lead

Responsibilities:

Review and implementation of SAP development guidelines on the project

Create a common library of reusable development objects

- Review and adjustment of ATC variants for code base static checks
- Sprint planning, monitoring, and preparation for development
- Estimation of development tasks
- Allocating tasks among team members
- Presenting sprint results to stakeholders in demo sessions
- Communication with the Customer's In-house Team
- Investigating and improving bottlenecks in existing implementations
- Transport requests management
- Conducting code reviews and refactoring

Tools and Technologies:

 Smartforms, SAP Core Data Services, SAP BAPI/RFC, SAP ABAP in S/4HANA, OData, Enhancement Framework, ABAP Objects, ABAP Core, Postman, Eclipse with ABAP Development Tools, ABAP Workbench Tools, Oracle RDBMS, HANA

Nov-2023 - Till now - EPAM Systems, https://www.epam.com

Customer: Syngenta AG (Commerce)

Project Roles: Key Developer

Responsibilities:

- Development of RFCs to integration with external non-SAP system
- Investigation and creation business object events based on the SAP NetWeaver Add-On for Event Enablement
- Extending the functionality of standard business objects
- Enhancement of standard SAP functionality for raising custom events
- Implementation of outbound messages monitoring
- Making changes to printable documents based on smartforms

Tools and Technologies:

 BAPI, RFC, SAP Business Objects, SAP Business Object events, SAP NetWeaver Add-On for Event Enablement, Smartforms, SAP Netweaver 7.5, ABAP Workbench, Soap UI, Oracle RDBMS

Feb-2023 - Aug-2024 - EPAM Systems, https://www.epam.com

Customer: EPAM Systems (Software & Hi-Tech)

Project Roles: Developer

Responsibilities:

- Full stack applications development (ABAP + SAPUI5)
- Adjusting data exchange between SAP and non-SAP systems and services (AWS, Datalake)
- Implementation of PostgREST interface between SAP and Datahub
- Encrypt / decrypt data with HashiCorp Vault service
- Reorganization of data encryption / decryption infrastructure on the project
- Implementation of infrastructure for creating Swagger descriptions of project http-services
- Creation of advanced customizing tables based on cluster of maintenance views
- Dynamic programming and DB updating
- Enhancing standard transactions by adding new screen fields and their processing logic
- Development of email notifications
- · Writing unit-tests for backend and frontend developments
- System performance analysis

Tools and Technologies:

 ABAP OO, ABAP CDS, AMDP, OData, SAPUI5, HTTP-services, Email templates, ALV grids, PostgREST, Background jobs, ABAP Platform 2021, ABAP Workbench, SAP Gateway Service Builder, Eclipse (ABAP Development Tools), Postman, DBeaver, Visual Studio Code, abapGIT, Swagger, MS Excel, SAP HANA

Aug-2021 - Jan-2023 - EPAM Systems, https://www.epam.com

Customer: EPAM Systems (Software & Hi-Tech)

Project Roles: Key Developer, Development Team Lead

Responsibilities:

- Technical design and back-end development of Tax Compliance Tracking Tool (TCTT) application
- Technical design and back-end development of Accrual Trend module for FC Checklist application
- Development of backend part of reports for the Fiori application
- Development and enhancement OData services using SAP Gateway
- Development of applications using the BOPF architecture based on CDS
- Development of http-service for integration with SSO (OAuth 2.0)
- Integration with email processing automation system
- Add encrypt / decrypt functionality for FC Checklist attachments
- Participation in HashiCorp Vault configuring
- Participation in development of PostgREST API component for data receiving from Datalake
- Creation and usage authorization objects to differentiate roles within an application
- Working with integrated functions of third-party services, such as AWS S3, HashiCorp Vault
- Development of email notifications using SAP Email Templates functionality
- Filters correction for OData service using Code-Based Implementation

Tools and Technologies:

 ABAP OO, ABAP CDS, AMDP, OData, HTTP-services, Email templates, ALV grids, PostgREST, Background jobs, ABAP Platform 2021, ABAP Workbench, SAP Gateway Service Builder, Eclipse (ABAP Development Tools), Postman, DBeaver, MS Excel, SAP HANA

Aug-2010 - Jul-2021 - Unitary Enterprise A1, https://a1.by

Customer: Unitary Enterprise A1 (A1 Telekom Austria Group)

Project Roles: Key Developer

Responsibilities:

- Creation of complex reports (ALV, Dynpro)
- Development of business programs for the mass creation of FI, MM, SD and other documents
- Creation of printable forms (smartform, PDF, Word, Excel), including OXML
- Creation and support of interfaces between SAP and other systems (files, web-services)
- Extension of standard programs and transactions with custom functionality using BADI, userexits, enhancements
- Support for updating the system to the new version of SAP Basis
- Download data with service programs and LSMW
- Creation and maintenance of background jobs
- SQL tuning and performance optimization
- Creation of multilanguage interfaces
- Search of notes with the SAP support portal for troubleshooting
- · Writing technical and user documentation

Tools and Technologies:

 ABAP OO, ALV grids, Printable forms (smartform, PDF, Word, Excel including OXML), Data upload/download, BAPIs, Application Log, XML, Web-services, BADIs, Userexits, Enhancements, LSMW, SAP Query, Background jobs, SAP Netweaver 7.5, ABAP Workbench, Adobe Lifecycle Designer, Soap UI, MS Excel, Oracle RDBMS

Jan-2018 - Jun-2021 - Unitary Enterprise A1, https://a1.by

Customer: Unitary Enterprise A1 (A1 Telekom Austria Group)

Project Roles: Key Developer

Responsibilities:

- · Changing the electronic document flow system for integration with the RE-FX module
- Development of an interface for the automatic creation of RE-FX contracts based on contract cards of the electronic document flow system
- Development of an interface for the automatic change of the payment terms of RE-FX contracts based on additional agreement cards of the electronic document flow system
- Development of a program for loading and updating address data provided by the National Cadastral Agency (NCA) (csv files)
- · Extension of the architectural object card and the RE-FX contract card user functionality
- Support of uploading data to AWP Declarant

Tools and Technologies:

ABAP OO, BAPIs, BADIs, ALV grids, Data upload/download, Application Log, Background jobs, SAP Netweaver
 7.5, ABAP Workbench, MS Excel, Oracle RDBMS

Nov-2014 - Dec-2017 - Unitary Enterprise A1, https://a1.by

Customer: Unitary Enterprise A1 (A1 Telekom Austria Group)

Project Roles: Key Developer

Responsibilities:

- Development of electronic document cards using the DFS framework
- Integration of electronic document cards with the EDI-provider's EDS signing tool (EDS Signer)
- Development of the XML interface between SAP ERP and the EDI-provider's connection tool (EDI Connector)
- Development of functionality for signing multiple documents in a zip-archive
- Integration with the service of signing documents using a mobile digital signature
- Creation of printable forms of documents (PDF)
- Development of functionality for mass printing of a package of documents
- Writing technical and user documentation

Tools and Technologies:

 ABAP OO, ALV grids, Printable forms (PDF), Data upload/download, XML, Enterprise services, Application Log, Background jobs, SAP Netweaver 7.5, ABAP Workbench, SAP Content Server 7.50, Adobe Lifecycle Designer, Altova XMLSpy, AvCSP, EDS Signer, EDI Connector, MS Excel, Oracle RDBMS, MaxDB

Jun-2011 - Oct-2014 - Unitary Enterprise A1, https://a1.by

Customer: Unitary Enterprise A1 (A1 Telekom Austria Group)

Project Roles: Developer

Responsibilities:

- Development of the EDS infrastructure configuration for local machines and VDI
- Development of the automated uploading of custom EDS certificates
- Participation in the integration of EDS Avest into SAP ERP (SAP SSF)
- Changing signing process of printable forms of documents to signing using EDS
- Development of functionality for mass signing of a package of documents
- Creation of printable forms of documents (Word, Excel, PDF)
- · Writing technical and user documentation
- Training users to work with new functionality

Tools and Technologies:

ALV grids, Printable forms (PDF, Word, Excel), Data upload/download, Application Log, LSMW, Background jobs,
 SAP Netweaver 7.0, ABAP Workbench, SAP Content Server 6.50, AvCSP, MS Excel, Oracle RDBMS, MaxDB

Apr-2008 - Jul-2010 - JV CJSC MAZ-MAN, http://en.maz-man.by

Customer: JV CJSC MAZ-MAN

Project Roles: Development Team Lead, Project Manager

Responsibilities:

- Development and support of the accounting system of the company
- Support for accounting systems of subsidiaries
- Identification of problems and needs of the current processes of the company

- · Coordination of actions of the development team and system administrators
- Purchase and maintenance of IT equipment and software
- Support and configuration of company servers (Internet, file, e-mail)
- Support and extension of the local corporate network
- Support and extension of the numbering capacity of the private automatic branch exchange (PABX)
- Working with suppliers and contractors in the IT field

Tools and Technologies:

 Active Directory, Ethernet, SMTP, POP3, IMAP, ODBC, Printable forms (1C, Word, Excel), Data upload/download, Data composition system (DCS), Query Builder, Report Builder, 1C:Enterprise 7.7, 1C:Enterprise 8.1, MS Excel, MS SQL

Sep-2004 - Apr-2008 - JV CJSC MAZ-MAN, http://en.maz-man.by

Customer: JV CJSC MAZ-MAN

Project Roles: Key Developer

Responsibilities:

- Support and extension of functionality for the following system modules
- Maintaining design and technological documentation
- Calculation of the requirements for materials at each stage of the production process
- Formation of the cost of finished products
- Maintenance of warranty and post-warranty service
- Conducting procurement operations and monitoring reorder points
- Monitoring of warehouses in real time
- Reservation of goods at the request of customers
- Quality control of finished products

Tools and Technologies:

ODBC, Printable forms (1C, Word, Excel), Data upload/download, Data composition system (DCS), Query Builder,
 Report Builder, 1C:Enterprise 7.7, 1C:Enterprise 8.1, MS SQL

<u>Jul-2003 - Aug-2004</u> - LLC Softgarantservice, https://www.sgs.by

Customer: The companies of the commercial sector

Project Roles: Developer

Responsibilities:

- Development of documents and reports for production processes
- Development of programs and reports for calculating depreciation of fixed assets
- Development of programs and reports for payroll calculation
- · Conversion and loading of initial data from old systems
- File interfaces between company's systems
- Transfer of systems to a new chart of accounts
- Development of printable forms (1C, Word, Excel)
- Installing and configuring software

Tools and Technologies:

ODBC, Printable forms (1C, Word, Excel), Data upload/download, 1C:Enterprise 7.7, MS SQL